Guide to the Sala Udin Papers, 1980-2005 AIS.2006.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence, 1995-2005; V.
  - Association for the Study of African American Life and History, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Black Action Society, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Bloomfield-Garfield Corporation, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Boy Scouts of America, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Cards, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Cards, 2000-2003 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Cards, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Cards, 2002-2003 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Center for Family Excellence, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Center for Global Studies, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Charms, Inc. - Sickle Cell Society, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Church and Communities Pulling Together, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Claim, Inc., 2000 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Constituent concerns regarding property reassessment, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Coro Center, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Jim Ferlo, 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Government Finance Offices Association, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Hate mail, 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Incoming correspondence, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Incoming correspondence, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Incoming correspondence, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - K. Leroy Irvis, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Kudos - Thank You notes, 2004-2005 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Letters of support, 2004-2005 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Market Rug Company, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - National Italian American Foundation, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Outgoing correspondence, 2004-2005 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Pittsburgh Downtown Partnership, 2004-2005 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Pittsburgh School Board, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Governor Ed Rendell, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Resumes, 2003-2005 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Squirrel Hill Urban Coalition, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Theiss Development Center, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - U.S. Airways (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Jake Wheatley, 2004-2005 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Wecht Law Firm, 2004-2005 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Freedom Corner, 1991-2005; VI.
  The Freedom Corner series is comprised of materials related to the establishment of a monument at Centre Avenue and Crawford Street in the Hill District of Pittsburgh. The Freedom Corner was the former site of a billboard that depicted messages of opposition concerning a 1950s urban renewal plan to raze houses in the Hill District. It gradually became a rallying point for local marches and civil rights demonstrations. In 1992 the Hill District Project Area Committee sought to erect a sculpture at the site, but it would take until 2001, under the leadership of City Councilman Sala Udin, before Freedom Corner Monument was ultimately finished.
  The Freedom Corner series includes construction and contract files; correspondence; design proposals for the monument; events and dedications; financial records; newspaper and press clippings; nominations and votes for people to be included on the monument both living and dead; photographs; promotional and educational publications; research related to Freedom Corner; and various Freedom Corner committees' documents, membership lists or directories, plans, and proposals. The series is broken down into ten subseries.
  - Committees, 1.
    - General Body Committee, 1998-2001 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Member and attendees lists, 1998-2000 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Planning Committee proposal, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Public Relations Committee, 1998-2000 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Urban League, 1995-1999 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2.
    - 1998-2002 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Byrd Brown, 1998-2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Drafts, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Torch of Freedom Award Winners Marion Jordan and Monsignor Charles Owen Rice, 1999-2001 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Design, 3.
    - Ideas and proposals, 1991-1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Freedom Corner Survey, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Carlos Peterson artwork, 1999-2003 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Events, 4.
    - April 21, 2001 Freedom Corner Dinner, 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Opening and dedication, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Construction and Contracting, 5.
    - Agreements, 1996-1999 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - BD&E (Barton Denmarsh Esteban, Inc.), 2003 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Blacksher Electric, 2001-2004 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Freedom Corner upgrades, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Graves Architects, 1997-2004 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Grogan and Graffam, 2001-2003 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Lami Grubb Architects, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Kiosk designs, budgets, and proposals, 1999-2002 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Mechanic's Lien - Cold Spring Granite Company versus URA of Pittsburgh and Hill District Construction Development Company, 2001-2003 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Various contracts, subcontracts, and proposals, 2000-2004 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Capca Contracting, 2001; 1.
      - Graciano Corporation, 2001; 2.
      - Milestone New Media Group, 2004; 3.
      - General subcontracting, 2000-2003; 4.
      - Turner Construction Company, 2001; 5.
      - Web address, 2004; 6.
  - Finances, 6.
    - Allegheny Regional Asset District budget, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Contributions, 1998-2002 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Cost estimates, 1999-2001 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Financial report and statements, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Foundation grid, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Fundraising reports and agenda, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Grant information, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Invoice selection sample, 1998-2001 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Pacesetters, 1998-2000 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Living Legends and Fallen Heroes, 7.
    - Fallen Heroes ballots and proposals, 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Living Legends ballots and proposals, 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Name Honor Ring, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Nominations and biographies, 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Selection Committee, 1999-2001 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Pamela A. Smoot objections to selections, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Photographs, 8.
    - Freedom Corner march, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Promotional Materials, 9.
    - 2001 Program brochure - corrected copy (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Flyers, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Graphic forms (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Learner's Guide, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Press releases, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Souvenir booklet - History of the Freedom Corner, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Subject Files, 10.
    - Allegheny Conference on Community Development, 1996-2002 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Civil Rights Movement in Pittsburgh by Larry Glasso, circa 2001 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Clippings, 1998-2002 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Freedom Corner Collaborative oral history proposal, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Research, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Stationary (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Things-to-do notes, March 30, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 50)
- Mason Tillman Associates, Ltd., 1998-2000; VII.
  In 1995 the Pittsburgh City Council formed the Disparity Study and Implementation Commission. The commission was charged to review how effective its M/WBE policies had been, to create new policy that could withstand potential legal challenges, and to encourage changes that could allow the city to further achieve its goals of eliminating discriminating in contracting. In 1999 the commission hired California-based Mason Tillman Associates (MTA) to conduct a series of disparity analyses regarding the success of W/MBE contracting done by the city. MTA examined service contracts awarded by the city and its five authorities between 1996 and 1998 to determine whether city contracts were utilizing minority and women contractors. The final report, of which the executive summary was written by Councilman Udin, found that no construction contract over $250,000 had been awarded to any W/MBE. Among other findings the MTA reports conclude that no architectural or engineering contracts had been awarded to minority businesses and describe a variety of general discriminatory conditions for W/MBE business owners including pressure for them to lower prices or increase their amount of work without raising their bid.
  Materials in this series include the MTA's initial proposal to the City of Pittsburgh and its final report.
  - City of Pittsburgh Contracting and Procurement Study Proposal, August 31, 1998; 1.
    The City of Pittsburgh Contracting and Procurement Study Proposal is Mason Tillman Associates initial proposal addressed to Councilman Udin to conduct the Disparity Study and Implementation Commission's contracting disparity study.
    - RFP Number: DSIC-1 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - RFP Number: DSIC-2, August 31, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - City of Pittsburgh Contracting and Procurement Study Final Report, September 2000; 2.
    City of Pittsburgh Contracting and Procurement Study Final Report is Mason Tillman Associates final report on contract disparity for women and minority businesses in Pittsburgh.
    - Vol. 1: Legal History, Anecdotal, and Laws and Policies (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Vol. 2: City of Pittsburgh (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Vol. 3: Urban Redevelopment Authority of Pittsburgh (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Vol. 4: Housing Authority of the City of Pittsburgh (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Vol. 5: Public Parking Authority of the City of Pittsburgh (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Vol. 6: Stadium Authority of the City of Pittsburgh (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Vol. 7: Pittsburgh Water and Sewer Authority (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Vol. 8: Executive Summary (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Contacts, Telephone Numbers, Form Letters, Request Forms, Etc., 2000 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Neighborhood Files, 1987-2005; VIII.
  The Neighborhood Files series includes materials related to specific neighborhoods within Pittsburgh's District 6 or related to Sala Udin's general political interests, including the Hill District, Downtown, the Northside (including Manchester), Mt. Washington, Oakland, and the Strip District between the years 1987-2005. Subjects include: revitalization, development, housing, crime and public safety, and the Hill District Community Development Corporation.
  - District 6, 1.
    The District 6 subseries contains materials related to abandoned or condemned buildings existing throughout District 6.
    - Condemned buildings, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Downtown, 2.
    The neighborhood of Downtown resides within Councilman Udin's District 6. Subjects within this subseries include materials primarily on improving the livability of downtown Pittsburgh as well as its development and revitalization.
    - Aggressive panhandling legislation, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Allegheny Riverfront Park, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Centre City Towers Community Report, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Development and Revitalization of the Fifth and Forbes Area of Downtown Pittsburgh, and Plan C Task Force materials, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Pittsburgh Downtown Living Initiative - A Collaborative Strategy for Downtown Living in Pittsburgh report, 2001-2004 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Pittsburgh Downtown Living Initiative - The Vacant Upper Floors Project, June 2004 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Pittsburgh Downtown Partnership (PDP), 1996-2003 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Pittsburgh Downtown Partnership (PDP) - Downtown Circulation Operations Plan and Implementation Strategy, January 2005 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Pittsburgh Downtown Partnership (PDP) - Downtown Circulation Operations Plan and Implementation Strategy - Supporting Documentation Report, January 2005 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Pittsburgh Downtown Partnership (PDP) - Downtown Planning Collaborative Final Report and Coordinating Committee Executive Summary, 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Pittsburgh Downtown Plan, 1997-1999 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Plan C Task Force - A Framework for the Revitalization of Pittsburgh's Downtown Core report, February 27, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Residential living (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Sixth Street sidewalk construction, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Unban Marketing Collaborative - A Retail Strategy for Downtown Pittsburgh, Phase 1: Retail Action Plan, January 2000 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Working Group on Downtown Housing, 1998-2004 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Hill District, 3.
    The neighborhoods of the Hill District reside within Councilman Udin's District 6. Subjects within this subseries include materials related to the Hill District Community Development Corporation, crime and its prevention, revitalizing housing, improving educational opportunities, and general development of the neighborhoods including the addition of a supermarket.
    - Addison Terrace, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Allequippa Terrace, Hope VI Monthly Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - July 1-31, 1999 Activities Monthly Report, 1.
      - November 1-31, 1999 Activities Monthly Report, 2.
      - January 1-31, 2000 Activities Monthly Report, 3.
      - February 1-31, 2000 Activities Monthly Report, 4.
      - March 1-31, 2000 Activities Monthly Report, 5.
    - Arcena Street (Ridgeway Street), 2003 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Bedford shooting, 1999-2002 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Bedford - McCormack Baron, 2002-2003 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Bedford Hill - Construction, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Bedford Hope 6, 2000-2004 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Centre Avenue - Omni Management, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Centre Avenue Redevelopment, 1998-2004 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Centre Street - Stakeholders and "New Markets", 2001-2004 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Chamber of Commerce, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Cliff Street Block Club, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Hill District Community Development Corporation (CDC), 2000-2005 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - CDC - Audits, 2000-2004 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - CDC - Board of Directors, 1999-2001 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - CDC - Board of Directors, 2002-2005 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - CDC - Business Plan, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - CDC - Correspondence, 1999-2004 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - CDC - Crawford Square, 1993-2001 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - CDC - Contracts, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - CDC - Newsletters, 1999-2004 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - CDC - Organizational Information, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - CDC - Personnel Policy, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - CDC - Report - A Business and Commercial Strategy for the Hill Community, October 8, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - CDC - Town Meetings, 1998-2000 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - CDC - Vacant Property Work Group, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Community Health Assessment, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Consensus Group (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Crawford Square, 1995-2004 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Crawford Square - Letters of Agreement, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Crime map, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - DLC Urban Core, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Drugs and crime - Narcotics and Vice Unit and Evaluation of Weed and Seed project, 1999-2002 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Education Council, 1999-2002 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Education Council, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Education Council, 2004-2005 (Box 11, Folder 21)
      Includes 1 CD-ROM
    - Grocery/Supermarket, 1998-2004 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Grocery/Supermarket - Steven Paul Urban Reinvestment Proposals (SPUR) - Centre Avenue Supermarket Development reports, 2004-2005 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Growth Fund, 2003-2005 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Housing (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Investments in the Hill District report, February 11, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Leadership structure, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Maintenance programs, 1999 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Master Plan Study of the Mellon Area Site, Melody Tent Site and the Center/Wylie Corridor in the Hill District, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Master Plan Update, University of Pittsburgh, East Campus District, Hillside District, and Hilltop District Final Draft, March 3, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Melody Tent, 1998-2000 (Box 11, Folder 31.)
    - Mural, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Neighborhood map (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - New Granada Theater, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Oak Hill, 2000-2004 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Oak Hill Apartments Master Plan updates, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Oak Hill Development Partnership Plan, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Off-the-Street Construction Program, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - One Hope Square, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Parking Study for Hill District Area, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Pittsburgh Partnership for Neighborhood Development, 1997-2001 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Penguin's Arena, 2001-2005 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Reed Street, 1998-2001 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Reports and proposals, 1987-1996 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Resource Center agenda, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Retreat for Hill District Planning, July 2000 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Schenley Heights - Robert William Park (5 prints) (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Shootings, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Task Force, 1998-2002 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Urban Design Associate Plans, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Uptown Community Action Group, 1995-2002 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Manchester, 4.
    The neighborhood of Manchester resides within Councilman Udin's District 6. Subjects within this subseries include public safety and education.
    - Community Safety Initiative, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Historical Society, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Manchester Academic Charter School, 1998-2001 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Manchester Citizen's Corporation, 1995-2004 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Neighborhood Transformation Initiative, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Ten-year Community Revitalization Plan, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Youth Development Center, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Mt. Washington, 5.
    The subseries for the neighborhood of Mt. Washington is primarily conmprised of tax related materials within that neighborhood.
    - 1999-2003 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - 2004-2005 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Unpaid taxes, 1998-2004 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Northside and North Shore, 6.
    The neighborhoods of Northside and North Shore reside within Councilman Udin's District 6. Subjects within this subseries include planning and development, tourism, and interactions with neighborhood leaders.
    - Allegheny West, 1997-1998 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Alpine Avenue, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Alpine Tot-Lot Gardens, circa 2002 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Central Neighborhood Council, 1999-2005 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Civil Development Council, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Clark Bar sign, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - "Developing Communities" - newsletters of Northside Community Development, March 2003 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Federal Hill Development Study, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Federal North, 1996-2002 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Fineview, 1997-2000 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Golden Glass Cathedral, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Leadership Conference, 2004-2005 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Leadership Conference correspondence, 2000-2001 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Neighborhood Business District Revitalization Program, 1987-2002 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Northside Coalition for Fair Housing, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Northside Chronicle newspapers, 2004-2005 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - North Shore Connector reports, 1999-2002 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - North Shore Master Plan draft, October 2002 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Perry South Real Estate (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Spring Garden Neighborhood Council, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Tourism Visitation report, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - World War II memorial, 2002-2004 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Oakland, 7.
    The neighborhood of Oakland resides within Councilman Udin's District 6. Subjects within this subseries include planning and development.
    - Future of Oakland Strategy, circa 2002 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Planning and Development Corporation, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Schenley Gardens, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Schenley Plaza Closure, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Strip District, 8.
    The neighborhood of the Strip District resides within Councilman Udin's District 6. The only subject in this subseries is parking on Smallman Street.
    - Smallman Street Parking, 1996-1998 (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1995-2004; IX.
  The Newspaper Clippings series includes a variety of newspaper clippings from both newsprint and the Internet relating to subjects of interest to Sala Udin's personal and political interests including business, economics, history, housing, politics, race, religion, and Sala Udin.
  - Churches, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - City Council, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - City Council, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Civil War black soldiers and Udin as Frederick Douglas, June 25, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Crime, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Crime and police, 1999-2004 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Economics, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - GOP agenda, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Hill District grocery store, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Housing, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Miscellaneous, 1995-2003 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - News articles and releases about Udin, 2001-2004 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Obituaries, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Rob Penny death notice, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Newspaper articles on race, 2002-2004 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Revival article from New York Times, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 35)
- Pittsburgh Works, 1985-2004; X.
  The Pittsburgh Works series includes materials related to the City of Pittsburgh's local hiring ordinance. Pittsburgh Works was sponsored by Sala Udin and required that any construction contract using public money over $200,000 would employ 35% Pittsburgh residents and that any project entirely financed by the city would require 50%. Udin introduced the ordinance in 1998 primarily in response to jobs created by the $809 million Plan B stadium and convention center projects. The Works ordinance was approved by a referendum iniated by Udin and passed by city council in 2000. In 2001, the Pennsylvania State Senate amended Senate Bill 706 to prohibit the use of state funds on projects subject to municipal residency requirements thus severely limiting the effectiveness of the Pittsburgh Works ordinance.
  Materials include bills and ordinances, legislation, meeting agendas and minutes, proposals, press release, reports, research data, statistics, and studies between 1996 and 2001. Folders are arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Apprenticeships and training, 1996-2004 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Bills and Ordinances - Bills 594 and 595, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Bills and Ordinances - SB 706 and 1169, 1999-2003 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Bills and Ordinances - Bill 1742, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Bills, Ordinances, and Legislation - Bill 1759 (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Bills, Ordinances, and Legislation - Bill tracking reports by state, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Bills, Ordinances, and Legislation - Ordinance 14 and Executive Order on trades and training, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Bills, Ordinances, and Legislation - Ordinances related to Pittsburgh Works, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Bills, Ordinances, and Legislation - Pittsburgh Home Rule Charter Article 5 Amendment, 1998-1999 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Bills, Ordinances, and Legislation - Residents Job ordinance, 1998-2000 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Certified payroll form, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - City Controller Flaherty - Special Reports, 1997, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Job Creation in the Pittsburgh Construction Industry 1995-1996, September 1997; 1.